Sufyan Saleem

Date of Birth: 4 Jan 1996 Marital Status: Single

Address: Åsgårdvegen 19, A2, 9016 Tromsø Website: https://sufyansaleem.netlify.app/
Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

I am a 26 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

WORK EXPERIENCE

_		_	
Λі		~ /	
\boldsymbol{H}	u	<i>,</i>	10

July 2021 - present

Full Stack Developer

Working for this service provider agency, which provides smart solutions for managing rotations management and shift planning. My main roles include developing Hybrid Mobile Applications, Web Applications etc in a 50% position.

Linknbit

Dec 2020

MERN Stack Developer

Worked as part time project based remote MERN Stack developer.

Missoq

- Ecommerce StoreUnder Development
- Decklaration

Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

MERN Stack Engineer

Working for NY based design Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications, Backend and Hybrid Mobile Applications.

Mertium

Similar to Bloomberg.

Software Engineer

Medtigo

Provides services for hospitals

Remote, Norway

Remote

React, Nodeis, Express,

MongoDB, Digital Ocean

Remote

I developed the frontend based on template HTML, CSS, Less, React

I developed the Backend in Nodejs, Express, MSQL, Sequelize, Node mailer, Security for XSS and SQL Injection

Linknbit

Jan 2019 - May 2020

Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include

Islamabad, Pakistan

developing Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications.

Kyla App

- It is a Mobile App to know your laws
- Recommended actions
- Contact lawyer with location and details
- Paid and Unpaid Feature

Global Aviation System

For Central African Republic

Developed the backend in NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Node mailer, Geolocation, Security for XSS and NOSQL Injection

I am worked on parts of backend Node JS, Express, Sequelize CLI, PassportJS & Azure SQL, Swagger

Dynasty Unleashed Models

- Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers
- Users can register, create profile, add people and hire models at will

Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Deployment to Firebase & Google Play

Dokkani.co

- Ecommerce Mobile App.
- User can register, select products, add products to cart.
- User add products to wish list and checkout.
- Project was abandoned on last stage due to funds not provided and outsourced to someone else.
- My Version

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Woo Commerce API, Native Base

Yogurt App

 Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate. Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Native Base

SmartsAid

NGO App for refuges

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Firebase, Rest API, React Native Elements

2018 - FYP

Currency Recognition & Conversion

 Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and show the exchange rate in USD. Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB

2014 - 2018

Content Management Systems

Java, C#, MSSQL

Gym - Point of Sale

PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL

2010

RuneScape RPG

 Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game for you. Java

Note: For more projects checkout the website mentioned in the header of the resume.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

UiT, Tromsø (Aug 2020 – Dec 2022)

Internet of things and AI Specialist Course

PIAIC, Islamabad (2019), Only First Quadrant

BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

10 Matric, grade A

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE

Specialities

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

Social Links







Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo Vanilla JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB, MySQL, PostgreSQL HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI Git, Heroku, Netlify, Digital Ocean, Amazon Rest, GraphQL, MVC

Bash, Rust

Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES

Languages

English Urdu Pashto, Basic Norsk

Hobbies

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding, Boxing